July 29th when we have the FOMC, are
they going to raise rates? There's a
possibility, a good possibility, it's
like 35 to 40%, that they will. If they
don't, then I think Bitcoin will be
above 70,000 when that time comes
because I think people are going to
start factoring in the fact. What's
going on guys? Today we have a great
conversation with Jordy Visser. We talk
about what's going on with the AI
midcycle slowdown, why he thinks that's
over. Why is he getting excited about
Bitcoin? He thinks that the bottom is
forming. On top of that, we talk about
robotics, commodities, and what public
stocks Jury's getting interested in.
This conversation is full with lots of
nuance, and we cover some of the big
stories, things like Apple, and what's
going on with Meta or XAI and Grock. So,
you're going to enjoy it. Here's my
latest conversation with Jordy Visser.
All right, Jordy. This week, Grock and
Facebook both made very big
announcements about their uh ambitious
plans when it comes to AI. Looks like we
have a price war on our hands because
both of them started talking about
affordability for what they can actually
produce. Uh what's your take as to these
two kind of trying to make a comeback
and and take over OpenAI and Anthropic?
>> Uh so
ooh speechless now I I was trying to
think of the best way to kind of present
this. I I really am believing that uh we
have to start separating
everything going on in AI and the models
into two categories. I don't think
anyone anymore can catch up to anthropic
and open AAI and what their plans are.
Now, let me just kind of put that in
into context. I've spent a lot more time
on consumer agents. I've spent a lot
more time on what these models are
trying to do and what everyone's kind of
going for. They're all trying to get
some kind of revenue, all of them. So,
when Meta talks about the cloud
ambitions, they need some revenue coming
in the door now. And if your business is
going to be consumer agents,
advertising, stuff like that and
personal AI assistance where which is
where I am now putting officially Meta,
Apple, Google, Amazon. Now again, not
completely, but they all have that part
of the puzzle. Amazon, Google, and
Microsoft obviously not only have the
personal assistant, the co-pilot side,
they also have the cloud business.
Obviously, we have cloud business now
where we're renting out compute for
SpaceX. So, I think rather than get into
the model side, which again, these
models are just going to be
commoditized. Uh it's what what you're
aiming to get your revenues from. And
clearly, OpenAI and Anthropic are in a
war uh with the enterprise side. And
then everyone else to me is kind of
making sure that they're also spending
in other areas where they need this. And
obviously SpaceX,
you know, Tesla eventually, they've got
different ambitions for how they're
going to use AI. So I think I I'm not
really looking at the price wars as
anything more that number one, the media
is just kind of getting into this, oh,
the token index is going down. It means
we're going to have problems. I think
everyone's just reexamining where their
ROIC is going to come from, and they're
strategically moving their decision-m
towards that process.
>> I love when we uh maybe don't disagree,
but have slightly different takes on
this. Um, in building Sylvia, I think
you and I have talked in the last couple
of weeks about, you know, the mandate
from heaven 18 months ago. Everyone use
AI. Now all of a sudden people start
looking at the uh token prices or the
the compute, you know, cost on a monthly
basis was skyhigh. They all start
cutting that. But a lot of what people
have been doing both, you know, what
we've been doing at Sylvia, but also in
other companies I've talked with, they
essentially were changing the
architecture of how they use the models.
So it wasn't they were changing the
model. It was just hey we don't want to
ping the model for if you ask what the
date is or you know that type of stuff.
Right now I think that we've kind of
graduated past that and what we're
actively looking at and I think a lot of
other people are looking at is how do
you actually start to route queries to
different models based on the complexity
or the compute need of that query. And
so this feels like an area where you're
going to see a significant drop off in
the compute cost of these companies in
terms of what they're spending. And the
reason why that becomes interesting is
then it opens up this whole open- source
thing. And so to me, the Facebook and
XAI announcements around cost is
basically them trying to position
themselves to say, "Hey, maybe you don't
need to go to Chinese open source or
look for American open source. What if
you could use one of these closed source
models, but do it at a much cheaper
rate?" It's almost like they're
acknowledging the fact that all of these
companies are now becoming very
costconscious on this. I don't know if
it'll work. Like I don't know if they'll
actually drive more adoption, but it
seems odd that two different companies
who probably are not sharing their plans
with each other in the same week come
out and they're leading with, hey, this
is a cost-effective way to get super
intelligence, you know, via the model,
right?
>> Yeah. So, I I I don't agree with you, so
we'll keep going. Um I the part I agree
with is the fact that and and I I put
together a visual because a bunch of
people reached out and asked me the
question on from a variety of angles on
this point and then I had some people
that I've known a long time in the tech
side that are all bearish on this going
oh everyone's going to move to cheaper
model and I'm like that's we got to
start to understand where we are. So I'm
going to give it to you in a different
way. You've probably not heard it this
way. Um, and you're looking at it from
the angle of Sylvia, which I get. In my
opinion, having managed hundreds of
people over the years. Um, you bring in
a resume and you don't need to hire the
most expensive people throughout your
firm for every job. Jobs are now finally
getting delegated to the models that
make sense. Meaning 100 100 uh IQ might
be enough for something if it does if
you don't need it quickly. So, it's
getting back to the way I look at
aggregate payrolls, which is hours
worked, then you've got hourly earnings.
So, and how many people you're
employing, that is the aggregate
payroll. And I think every workforce is
figuring out
these models at the very high end,
they're super high IQ, they're very
cheap. And Dylan Patel gave an interview
that I listened to today on Wisdom Tree.
It's a great podcast. I highly
recommend. He talked about his spend.
So, this is Dylan Patel from Semi
analysis. Very sophisticated. His spend
went from $100,000 allin for his firm as
of uh December last year.
It's now 11 million ARS as he said,
annualized revenue spend. Now, what he
talked about as the importance of that
is he's not changing it. He's not
looking to get it done. He said in some
cases because the productivity is
expanding he's able to generate more
revenues. I think every business is
going to be different. I think for the
enterprises that had no usage for them
whatsoever they're figuring out where
they should be making the spend and in
some ca in every case they will be
having workflows that are using cheaper
models open source possibly. then you're
going to have more expensive high IQ
making decisions where they're very
effective and very cost effective
because they do the speed in onetenth or
1/100th the time that those workflows
do. So it just depends on where it is.
The end result is going to be a mixture
of all these different models.
Completely agree we were always going to
end up there. But I think one of the
things that's been challenging is that
since opus 4.5 the model intelligence
for coding agents just keeps getting
better and better. But the deployment
from enterprises just started and so
they spent the first six months actually
learning how much the spend would be.
Now they're going to start going through
a slight readjustment. Talente is
obviously out there promoting the fact
that you don't you know they're going
another angle. Oh, you don't want to
have this. You don't want to be exposed.
They're giving all the negatives to
having your own models. I think we're in
the price discovery phase for
everything. The models are going to keep
getting more efficient. They're going to
keep getting cheaper. they're going to
keep getting smarter. I think there's
going to be a mixture of both, but I
don't think this is going to affect the
overall spend. I think adoption and
usage is going up significantly
dramatically each day. Yeah. And and
maybe as a um a nuance to it, I actually
think that the number of tokens consumed
will continue to grow. So, I agree with
that. But I think that what companies
are trying to figure out, at least what
we're trying to figure out, is how do
you consume more tokens but spend less
money? And I think what we're starting
to see is that, you know, if you go hit
4.7 or 4.8 or, you know, whatever, uh,
and someone's asking what is the date,
not only is there a cost associated with
it, which obviously is a like a pain
point for the company, but there's a a
big latency. And so it's actually like a
bad experience for the user versus if
you can, you know, kind of hit a
lightning fast open source model, make
sure it's accurate, etc., then it
becomes uh somewhat interesting. Um, but
but some companies don't care, right?
They don't care about the cost. Maybe
Dylan Patellis is like, "Look, I'll
spend $50 million because every dollar
that I spend, I'm getting back $10 in
revenue." Then, you know, it kind of
doesn't matter, right?
>> Yeah. And that and that's the point is I
the the way this weeds out the bad
companies. And I I think his exact quote
was if you're not spending more money
every year, you're going out of
business. Like if you're trying to to
optimize based on I don't want to spend
X amount of dollars and you're cutting
back on your AI spend, it means you're
going out of business. And I happen to
agree with that. Meaning your budget for
AI should be expanding every single
year. No questions asked. It should
absolutely be going up. And that is the
only way you're going to survive as a
business. That makes companies that are
startups have a huge advantage. And
that's why semi analysis is very
different than say the se you know they
cover data centers they cover semi an
they cover semiconductors they cover the
entire AI buildout. If you're Goldman
Sachs and Morgan Stanley you've got a
huge payroll you have a huge thing
you're going to have a different
approach than a company that's just
starting was only spending $100,000 a
year on AI in December.
>> Yeah, that makes sense. Um what about
Apple? Apple obviously made the Siri
announcement um kind of an AI Siri uh
integration and then they also announced
that they're going to have to increase
prices because of uh memory. What do you
think's happening with that business?
I actually so
last week uh because I've been spending
so much time on Meta and because I've I
so I listen to more podcasts uh with
Meta involved. I listened to one with
Alex Cananteritz uh this week he had on
the CTO from Meta and I'll be covering
that in the YouTube. Whenever there's a
story that's going around that I'm
trying to figure out what's behind it.
They're getting into cloud. They're
saying the agentic world is is not at
where they thought it would be. Well,
then I got to go look up. So, I start
doing a ton of research on consumer
agents. And this is the way I want to
break it down for people as I get into
the Apple discussion. So far, all we've
done is coding agents. And I want people
to understand that that is basically the
language of AI. So we're using more
coding agents and that agentic side
where the workflows are getting longer,
they're getting more complex, they need
some kind of memory.
We've we've seen token usage go up
exponentially. Consumer agents are going
to make it have another move higher. And
in listening to Meta multiple times and
people talk about it, the complexity
with consumer agents and what has to go
on, the commerce side, the hey, book me
a trip to Italy. Here's what I care
about. That's far more complicated than
build me this spreadsheet, build me this
model. You have to do a lot more things.
You have to visit a lot more sites. It
takes a lot more compute. So the step
function of compute is going to go
exponentially when these guys can solve
this. The reason the Apple thing is
interesting is the same thing with Meta
because Google, Amazon, Amazon has
Alexa, Google has personal u
intelligence. Apple which is trying to
get Siri to work and then Meta which is
trying to monetize Facebook, Instagram,
everything they have in some way with
advertisements but also with AI combined
in as well as all these places having
some kind of hardware. Again, Alexa, uh
the phone, you go through it, everyone
has hardware out of this group. So the
question is think about the how
difficult it is that wow opus 4.8 8 4
point. We've got Fable 5, but yet Siri
still doesn't work. Alexa still doesn't
work. How's that possible? Well, the
complexity of what they're trying to
solve is impossible. I was in um my
Tesla using Grock again this week. And
Grock in a Tesla is phenomenal. The
latency is is is very good. Why can't
they do this with Siri? Well, the car is
on all the time. I'm just driving in it.
If you had your phone open all the time,
you could converse with chat GPT. It
would work. So, I think the most
interesting thing with Apple is the take
that I normally have. It sold off and
made all-time highs when they announced
Siri personal intelligence and they
showed what it was able to do. You had
some people saying it was horrible. You
had a lot of people saying it was
shockingly good. Then they had the
memory price side. Okay, memory prices
are going higher. We're going to have to
raise prices. The stock got hit both of
those days. On the Siri day, it made
all-time highs and sold off. And then it
sold off on the memory side, leaving it
down 10 more than 10% off the highs. And
then with no news, it went right back up
to the highs. This is not a cheap stock.
This tells me this is a bullish reaction
to bad news. And I like looking into
things. I think the market and
particularly the very smart people are
starting to look ahead to the next 6
months. So, this is the first warning
I'm going to give to people. Uh, the
infrastructure trade was a great
six-month trade. I still think you're
going to make a lot of money being along
the receivers or the the people getting
the money on the infrastructure
buildout, but it's not going to be as
easy. So, I'm calling the the AI
midcycle slowdown is over when it comes
to terms of I think now everyone's a
little bit too negative on the AI
buildout side and they're worried about
this compute thing. Where I think this
is all shifting to is two themes. One is
when consumer agents come, you have to
repric Apple, you have to repric Meta,
you have to repric these stocks because
the ROIC is going to come through. And I
think people are getting more bullish on
these companies with the reality that
that's coming. The second angle is this
is where you start getting into the
crypto side because of the agentic
commerce. They're linked together. And
so I'm looking towards, you know, a year
from now, the major story being how did
we miss Apple? I'm not convinced in meta
yet because it doesn't have the same
technical picture, but I am going to
watch the hyperscalers much more closely
because I think we're getting into a
side where the surprise could be that
we're moving into consumer agents and
away from the coding agents.
>> What do you do with Grock in your Tesla?
>> This was real really more
conversational. So, I wanted in fact the
irony is I wanted to have conversation
about exactly what I just talked about.
So, the way that I I use it when I'm
driving, especially in Maine, for say an
hour and I've just listened to a
podcast, I will pause the podcast. I
will go to Grock and I will now have a
conversation to expand that
conversation. It's much better in the
car than it is walking around with
chatt. And the reason is because it's on
all the time and the signal is much
better inside the car. So, Grock is more
humanlike for me having the
conversation. And so again, this thing
of having a conversation with a really
smart person, it's literally, hey, I
want to talk about Apple and Meta and
consumer agents. And I'll just give you
one, you know, one factoid that came out
of that. Goldman Sachs had a report out
this year saying consumer agents will
consume about 30 times
30 times what coding agents will consume
from a compute basis. This is why there
is no solution to compute. If you think
there is excess capacity of compute, you
are absolutely wrong.
>> Ladies and gentlemen, I'm a software
guy, but every once in a while, I come
across a piece of hardware that I just
simply can't live without. And that's
plaid for me. Now, now this whole thing
is basically a hedge against me losing
my memory because when I have all these
conversations, I talk to founders,
investors, all kinds of people every
single day. There's three things that I
always want to take away from the
conversation. What I learned, what are
the next steps, action items, and then
what notes do I need to remember for
some period in the future? You can even
mark important moments during the
discussion so that you can quickly
reference them later. Whether it's a
founder meeting, an investor call, a
podcast interview, or maybe even just
want to sit down and talk to your
spouse. I could instantly go back and
forth and find key insights, decisions,
action items that I talked about in that
conversation. Over time, every
conversation all of a sudden becomes an
asset instead of a forgotten moment. And
in a world where information is
abundant, the ability to retain and
leverage knowledge is a very real
competitive advantage. That's why Plaude
Note Pro caught my attention recently.
It's a credit card sized notetaker.
Slim, portable, perfectly integrated
with my phone. And the part that I love
about it is that it automatically
captures conversations. It turns it into
board ready summaries. You can have
structured action items and it does
flawless transcription. It is really
magical and you should try it out. So go
check them out. This hardware has
completely changed my life and I think
that you'll end up finding it very
valuable. So if you want to use Plaude
and get the same value out of it that
I've gotten out of it, go check them out
at plaude.ai/pmp.
You can go to plaude.ai/p ai/pom and get
15% off if you use the code pump or just
go click on the link in the description.
So go to plaud.ai/pmp
today. Now when we look at the compute
issue, obviously that's one of the big
things. People saw uh Meta's
announcement, they start getting worried
about that. Um we continue to see
volatility in a lot of these names. Uh
Bloom Energy, now there's a bunch of
these short reports that are starting to
come out. It almost feels like the
people who are pessimistic, they are
just waiting to pick their shot and they
think that all this stuff is overvalued.
Can short sellers make money in a market
like this? Like how do you think about
the other side? Right? You're bullish on
this. I'm bullish on this. Many people
are buying these names. What about the
other side? Like do they have any uh
credible critiques that you think uh
people should pay attention to?
>> Well, of course. Listen, let's go back
to me um selling out of Micron but still
believing the memory trade is going to
continue. Um in fact, one of the things
just to give people a a preview. Um I
part of the reason I I sold out of
Micron was because the speculation
everywhere was starting to become
evident. Um and again it it was
leverage.
So when I see leverage forming and
obvious in Korea and I see leverage in
macro strip strategies and I see
leverage in fundamental long short
strategies where 6 months ago they were
arguing with me on memory already being
expensive and now they're bragging about
the fact that this has 5 years to go. I
just start to reduce the risk and I
think there's better places to put my
money. Um, and now I have to get my
brain around the fact that to buy Micron
back, I'm going to have to buy it above
where I sold it. There's absolutely no
question. Now, I don't have a problem
with that because I've been a trader my
life. But I do think that there are ways
Micron went up to 1300. So, if you sold
it at, you know, 1250 and you bought it
back at 900, you can trade, you know,
bubbles, parabas, and all these things
that I've talked about, you will have 30
to 40% corrections. And a lot of the
these names, we've had some of the
largest corrections in the history of
their stocks. And that's that's, you
know, serious. Samsung uh over a 10-day
period was down 20%. Um and that's
despite
making uh enough money to basically to
be more than they've made in their
40-year history. That's what's expected
for this year. So, you can have price
falls. You can short Bloom Energy. I
just think people are making a mistake
if they're thinking about this longer
term. My general rule is as a macro
person, I try to find which way the
river is flowing and I'm either in that
side of the river going up or I'm just
not in the trade. And that's the way I
thought about micron. I still think
you'll see 4,000 5,000 in micron before
this is done. I think it'll be harder to
ride it from a,000 to 5,000 than it was
to go from 100 to 500. And that's my
general take is I I'm going to trade it
more often. I'll get out. I'll get in
and I'll look for points. Uh but I do
think for people who want to short them,
they just have to have a shorter time
horizon.
>> You mentioned Samsung. Talk a little bit
about them. They reported these like
blowout earnings, but they sold off.
What What's going on there?
>> Yeah, like I said, I mean, the numbers
are astonishing. And for people who who
just haven't read the story,
they're they're expected to make $217
billion dollar this year. I mean I with
a B with a B that's how much they're
expected to make not the revenues how
much they're or earnings are supposed to
be this year over the last 40 years they
haven't made a combined $217 billion. So
you have to put that in the context and
realize that number one when people say
this is a bubble it's not a bubble like
the earnings are massive. Number two,
the amount of chips they're selling and
how far into the future they're going to
be selling this stuff. It's just not
easy to build memory capacity. So
Samsung along with SKHEX and Micron have
benefited significantly and they're
going to continue to benefit
significantly. But like I said, if you
go back over the last 25 years, the the
the only time they had a correction
greater than 20% over a 10day period, I
believe, was when the world shut down
for a virus that was going to kill
everyone, and it was very similar to one
that happened just after Lehman
Brothers. Those are the only two times
in 25 years. And yet, it's still near
the all-time highs, even though it's off
20% and it's still a parabola. Here's
the thing I would say. I saw a lot of
people be very negative because one of
the things that we like to do is, hey,
they sold off on good news.
The problem is they were already down
15%
off the highs when that happened. So, I
I don't care about it nearly as much.
What I look for in those types of sell
the news things is when the stock is at
all-time highs, it opens higher and then
it sells off and it catches everyone and
then that usually leads to a two-month
or so correction. These things have been
correcting now for about 4 to 6 weeks.
And I say four to 6 weeks. Even though
they made new all-time highs, you
started to see the weakness in late May.
And that's when I really started to
pound the table on, okay, I really think
the AI midcycle slowdown is there. And
all we've done is wipe out the leverage
at this point across three buckets.
Systematic MA uh quant strategies have
been forced to take down their leverage.
We've also seen Korean investors uh
forced take down. We've seen the ETFs,
the two-time ETF in Hong Kong go down
62%. Like we've seen enough in my
opinion that we have a more balanced
market. And if you looked at what SKHENX
did with their ADR issuance and how
overs subscribed it was on the IPO
coming to the market, but then when you
read that most of the buyers or a lot of
the buyers were long only people, this
is the way long only managers are
showing their hand, which is they missed
this party on the way up. to move too
fast for how fast they deploy money,
they're going to be underneath to buy
things. So, I'm very comfortable that
we've done enough damage. Maybe we make
a little bit more new lows during
earning season, particularly on some
stocks, but the volatility is way too
high in the momentum side. It's going to
come down and it's going to come down
through lower correlation amongst the
names.
>> I know as the uh AI trade is maybe
gearing up to uh to get out of this
midcycle slowdown, uh you've become more
bullish on Bitcoin. What's going on
there?
Uh well, it's really I mean we talked
about it, but I'll just re-emphasize uh
a couple things and then I'll get into a
bigger topic that I'm starting to to to
say to managers and explain why I even
am starting a YouTube specifically on
crypto targeted for September. Uh as
people get to know me, uh I still I'll
always be a trader. I'll always look for
the best timing on things. But when
you're running a business, you want to
start things at a time when people are
going to start to be looking for them.
Um and I think uh this is a really
important story. So the first thing is I
always look for technical signs and I
finally got my first RSI divergence
since the peak uh at the end of last
year and that divergence was using
basically a 4hour RSI and I look for
points where the price makes new low
which happened when we broke through
60,000 recently but the RSI is higher
than it was at the prior low. plain and
simple. Now, that was the first time
that we got one. So, as a trader, I go,
"Well, now I can buy something when we
get back above 60 and I'll just stop
myself back out below the lows." That's
the way a trader trades and that's the
way that I've always thought. It's the
way I was brought up. And I'm an Elliot
wave guy and I still believe we're
entering a very, very big thing. My
belief is that over the course of the
next year, we are near the bottom end of
the range of Bitcoin. And see how I said
that, near. Could we go to 50? Yeah.
Could we go to 45? Yeah. Do I think
we'll be over 100 a year from now? Yeah.
So what do I care whether I buy
something at 60 or whatever? Yes, my my
percentage gain will be better, but if
we're above 100, I don't care. So that's
the first thing. The second thing is
I've highlighted that we probably all
underestimated, I know I did, the impact
that the AI capital suck would have from
the rest of everything. It's not just
Bitcoin people, it's the hyperscalers as
well. basically my benchmark arbitrage
of money rotating into the space that's
going the fastest. Micron went up 20
times. A 20 bagger. 20 bagger. You don't
get that in big companies and this is a
big company. So for that to happen,
you didn't need to buy Bitcoin. You
didn't need to buy crypto. You didn't
need to buy any of this stuff. Every
single person in Silicon Valley talked
about how startups, if you had AI
attached to it, nobody wanted crypto. At
the end of the day, people want to
invest in things that are working. And
so once it started to move lower, which
coincided in October with the release of
Opus 4.5, but it also coincided with
another strong secular trend that has
still been in place until last week,
which was rate cuts. We had 150 basis
points of rate cuts still in the market
as of October or late September of last
year. That peaked there. Some of it came
out because of the actual cut, but then
a lot of it came out because we started
to build in hikes. And we have about we
have a full cut plus percent of sorry
hike plus a hot probability of another
one before the end of the year. So
here's what I'm telling you is going to
happen in my mind. Um that's all going
to change or at least the rate of change
is going to be there. And I'm afraid of
change guys. I do not think they want to
hike. I did a piece on the Fed this week
and made sure that everyone was
highlighted that hey the Fed Walsh has
spoken. He believes AI is going to be a
productivity boom and that there might
be a point at the beginning where it's a
little inflationary before we get to
deflationary, but the last thing he
wants to do is go on some tight hiking
cycle because of inflation. We're going
to get a negative CPI print. The
question is July 29th when we have the
FOMC, are they going to raise rates?
There's a possibility, a good
possibility, it's like 35 to 40% that
they will. If they don't, then I think
Bitcoin will be above 70,000 when that
time comes because I think people are
going to start factoring in the fact
that maybe they're not going at all this
year before the midterms. Does he really
want to hike before the midterms when he
was brought in by Trump? So, I think
that may be on hold for a while. And
it's not that it's a big deal because it
means they're not cutting rates. But
since hikes are expected, it is a
positive relative to expectations.
Those are the ways that I'm kind of
looking at it. But I want to leave one
more thing for people and this gets into
the bigger picture. Scott Besson gave a
speech at the New York uh economic club
and I posted something on X uh on Friday
that Matt Hogan had put out. I do think
people should read the speech. I think
they should also read the op-ed from
Muhammad Alan on it. This is the fact
guys and we talk about it here. The
administration is very focused on
changing the way the US does business
around the globe and part of that change
is making sure that they don't lose the
control of the financial system or be
the leader of the financial guard rails.
He specifically said that digital
assets, tokenization,
stable coins are all part of the
administration's focus on this new
economic order. You have to understand
what that means. They are focused on
crypto being part of the guard rails and
this coincides with AI. So the reason I
named it AI macro nexus, the reason I do
my YouTube and it's about 90% a
combination of the impact AI is having
on the macro world we exist in today and
10% on crypto and what that means. We're
now at the point where the reason I'm
going to do YouTube where it's going to
be about 70% starting with crypto and
then showing the difference of the macro
world and AI connected to it is because
we are about to enter the AI agentic
commerce side which means the velocity
of money is going to increase. the
dormant assets that remain in the form
of housing, real estate around the globe
are going to be liqufied and turned into
active cash over the next five years
through tokenization. These are all
major positives and that's the reason
why I think you're at the beginning of a
multi-year bull market in Bitcoin. And
whether it starts in October, whether it
starts in December, or whether it starts
right now, I think we're at the bottom
end of the range for the next year.
I recently saw a statistic that showed
uh stable coins are spiking on the
weekends in terms of volume which makes
sense. The banks are closed, right? So
people want to uh access it. We also saw
the open stable coin a kind of
consortium that got announced. I think
they have like Mastercard and Visa and
Stripe. You a bunch of people all
participating in this and it just feels
like some of this is hey how do I get
into the stable coin game? But a lot of
it is the agents need money and what
money are they going to use, how are
they going to use this, whatever. Um, do
you see anything on that front or are
you hearing anything from fund managers
that suggests they're now starting to
move some of their funds into whether
it's stable coins or bitcoin or is this
more so you think we're pretty early in
this reversal and you're you're starting
to buy now because you know you think
that's what's people are going to be
doing 3 months from now. So price leaves
nar leads narrative. The first thing
that always happens in a bottom is you
start getting short covering because
people are frustrated that this has gone
on. I think Bitcoin has been a funding
side of the AI trade. I think um it
started when software got bludgeoned and
all of the software names got hit hard.
Uh and Bitcoin was part of it. I would
say anything built on code, you couldn't
get away from the correlation. So if you
wanted to hedge your semiconductors,
which now had high beta, you needed to
find high beta shorts. And high beta
shorts ended up being Salesforce.com,
Adobe, Adobe, Workday, and Bitcoin. And
I think all of those things became part
of the momentum trade. So it's not a
coincidence that as momentum has gone
down sharply that Bitcoin has a bid. So
for people want to be bearish like,
well, this is it just short covering.
All rallies that last for a year start
with short covering. every single one
because it means the narrative that was
existing before the AI infrastructure
trade is no longer as strong as it's
going to be and it's going to take a
while for that releveraging to happen
and as we go through earnings like I
said I think you're going to have
disappointments before every single name
was working. I don't think that's going
to be the case anymore in the AI trade.
I also don't think you can get five
baggers and six baggers over the course
of the next year. I think a lot of these
things are priced well. Dylan Patel
talked about it today and he said you're
going to see some surprises on the CPU
side and the surprise is going to be
that we've kind of gone a little too far
on the optics side. We've gone a little
too far. You're gonna he talked about
this. I think what all that means is
that that place is priced in a way where
if you can get 40% over the next year,
that's great. I think Bitcoin can do
more than 40% based on the fact that
just to get back to all-time highs,
you're talking about a double. and
getting back to all-time highs to me,
we'll be left with the narrative that I
just talked about. So, the first stage
is short covering. The second stage is
for the momentum to shift once we get
above the 200 day moving average, which
I've said that is the critical line. We
are still way below it right now. We
still I think it's around 76 77,000. So,
we still have quite a ways. We have 20%
before we get up there. So, this will be
a short covering rally. We'll see how it
goes. And like I talked about and for
people who who heard this before and
still reach out to me, are we still
watching Doge? Yes, I'm still watching
Doge for the energy side of crypto. But
I do think there will be uh surprising
news on what you said over the course of
the year where when people start to
realize that the 40name index that I've
created which goes through eight
separate verticals or sectors is a
direct overlay with Bitcoin that Bitcoin
just represents the ecosystem and I
think the ecosystem is going to benefit
from the stable from the agentic side
and that's going to flow to Bitcoin as
well.
Michael Sailor. The first Bitcoin sale
was like a dip in the, you know, dip
your toe in the water. The second one
was like a cannonball in the deep end.
The first time it sold off. The second
time he sold off a little bit, but it
almost seemed like the market was like,
"Ah, whatever." And they really didn't
care. So, you know, maybe he should get
some kudos for the way that he did this.
Um, and it's minimal impact on the
market with the big sale. But do you
take or read into that sale or or the
response from the market? Uh, a year
from now, this stuff is going to be
noise. Um, I'm actually a little
embarrassed to be associated with
something where we have to even talk
about this ridiculous thing. I I just
the Michael Sailor thing to me, um, he's
even become like people are blaming him
for why Bitcoin's not going higher.
Bitcoin, as we talked about, um, in
every asset you have corrections. I
don't get into four-year cycles. I don't
get into any of this stuff, but
the reality is what he has done and what
he has been able to do. I'm more focused
on the quantum side of crypto and the
solutions that are coming out and some
of the themes about should we just
basically deal with these tokens that
are dormant and should we the man owns
an enormous amount of supply of an asset
that I believe the world is going to
acknowledge is a real asset for
collateral and as we get into
tokenization and we start getting into
the dormant asset side I think people
will start to understand the value of
collateral again like they'll start to
understand what he has always talked
about. So I never bought into this
thing. I do agree that the most
important thing is that it's actually
higher than when he made his biggest
sale. That would be a sign that if you
would have said to people, hey, what
would happen if a week after he makes
his biggest sale the unthinkable that he
said he would never do publicly and even
though this is for a different reason,
so it doesn't count, but he did do it,
what would happen? Everyone would have
said the thing would be down big. So the
fact that it's higher I think is a Apple
type news item where it happened and
once you don't sell off after something
like that it actually is more of a
positive than a negative. So I don't
think this will ever be talked about
again in a big way. Today's episode is
brought to you by Uphold. Are you
someone who's tired of juggling multiple
apps just to trade, earn, stake, or
spend your crypto? Then listen up
because Uphold does all of that in one
single unified platform. You can access
300 plus crypto and fiat currencies with
an interface that works for you whether
you're a beginner or an expert. Uphold
also features any to any swaps where you
can swap crypto to fiat, fiat to metals,
and tokens to tokens directly in the
app. If you prefer self-custody,
Uphold's vault gives you multi-stick
security, key recovery, direct trading
access, and peace of mind without giving
up convenience. Uphold is also 100%
reserved, meaning no fractional
practices and proof of reserves are
updated every 30 seconds, so you can
verify your assets anytime. For US
users, you can even earn yield on
dollars with the USD interest account.
No fees, no minimums, and funds are
insured up to $2.5 million through the
Atomic Cash Suite program. If you want
one app for your entire digital asset
life, check out Uphold today. Go to
uphold.com to learn more. Uphold.com. Go
check them out today. Today's episode is
brought to you by mogul. $4 trillion.
That's how much real estate Deote says
moves onto the blockchain over the next
10 years. That's good news for the rest
of us because this year the VIX, Wall
Street's fear gauge, it ripped past 30.
The S&P went red and stocks repric every
time a politician tweets. Real estate
doesn't do that. Tokenization is the key
to giving everyone access to real
estate. Here's what most people don't
realize. You can invest in tokenized
residential real estate right now thanks
to Mogul. Mogul's founders come from
Goldman Sachs where they deployed
billions into real estate for
institutional clients. Now they
handpicked the properties and handled
the management for you. Historically, an
18% average annual IRRa that's 3x better
than their competitors. You get targeted
yields over 8% monthly rent payout, tax
benefits from depreciation, and zero 3
a.m. tenant calls. Over 100 properties
have already launched on Mogul. More
than 30,000 people have already signed
up, too. If you want in plus get a
special offer, head over to
mogul.club/p.
Again, that is mogul.com/p.
You can see important disclosures in the
description and head over to
mogul.club/p.
When you look at the market right now,
um, we've talked a lot about AI, talked
a lot about crypto. Are there are there
any areas that you're really excited
about or that uh you're you're starting
to deploy capital into that don't fall
into AI and crypto? or do you think
those are like the two games in town?
>> So, I am looking into the insurance
side. I'm looking into the regional bank
side. I've talked a lot about Eli Liy,
which is going to remain
Eli Liy. I I don't think even if it were
to go up, even if it were a threebagger
from here, I wouldn't get out of it. I I
have so much belief in what is happening
on the health side and the compounding
side of curing diseases and I want to be
associated with the group that's already
done sovereign AI. Uh, and I want to
make sure people hear that all this talk
you're hearing from people, well, you
should own your own models, you should
go through this. Remember what Anthony
and I talked about with Lily Pod and the
fact that on their campus they have a
thousand black wells. They have their
own sovereign AI. They are using that
with biotech companies. So, I'm going to
keep saying that healthc care is a big
thing. On my video last week, I did go
through some of the insurance names
which are now starting to see. I think
we're actually going into how important
agents are for companies that were
already using AI and that means a lot of
the banks are going to do well and
you've seen a lot of the banks make new
all-time highs. The regional banks have
made new all-time highs. regional banks
fit into a very interesting thing which
is it's very hard to buy a bank and take
them private um because of all the
regulations which means takeovers with
inside the regional banks for midsize
banks is probably going to happen
because as people put AI into their
model they can go buy companies and then
infuse them with AI and get rid of
headcount so it becomes very accretive
immediately so I think you're going to
see a lot of consolidation with inside
the financials and I think the
healthcare side and the insurance side
has already been spending money on this
and already advanced on it, they're
going to start seeing the benefits over
the next year.
>> What about outside of the public
markets? Are there anything in terms of
commodities or anything else that you're
starting to uh to get excited about?
>> Well, if I'm right about um
Bitcoin, then silver is going to do well
and gold's going to do well. It's not
going to be a resurgence of the um of
the debasement trade,
but it is going to be a hey, these
things were impacted more than we
thought from AI sucking the dollars out
of everything. And then secondly, the
reality that we have hikes built in. So
the run it hot thing turned into, hey,
we don't have any need for this. I I
wrote about this. I talked about it. We
still have a budget deficit that's
massive. And the reason that's important
is I don't think the Fed can raise
rates. So, one other angle is they raise
rates in July.
This could be a Michael Sailor type
moment as well because if they raise
rates, in my opinion, without any
question, it'll be a oneanddone and
it'll be a Fred a Fed credibility hike.
The long end's going to come down,
meaning yields are going to come down
and that would be the reason that they'd
be okay doing it. Every single macro
person I talk to when we've had good
conversations on this believes this. So
do I. That if they were to tighten in a
surprising manner in July as a
credibility hike, the long end would
come down. I think at that point people
would treat it as a one and done and for
the end of the year we have another 50%
of a hike built in. And so it could
actually act as a positive if it's a
dovish hike where he says we did this
for the credibility side. we are
committed to this but we think now we're
in a position where we can sit back and
wait. If that were going to happen which
I think is going to happen uh in terms
of if they did it they're going to do
that way uh I think that would be
positive as well. So I actually think
gold silver uh and bitcoin that
regrouping the debasement trade will
start to resur uh see a bottoming and a
rise as well.
Now, sometimes people will listen to
this and they should take away signal
from the things we talk about. There's
also times where they should take away
signal for the things we don't talk
about. And
the Iran war has been on again, off
again, on again, off again, off for
real. No, not anymore. And uh this past
week, we got uh I think whiplash, maybe
it was on and off twice. I don't, and
this sounds crazy, but I don't think
that the investment community really
cares anymore about the Iran war's
impact on their investments. Obviously,
there may be difference in terms of the
people who live in Iran or the the
military components, the geopolitics,
all that, but like from an investor
standpoint, I have not heard someone
talk about Iran impacting anything in
their portfolio in the last two weeks.
Maybe you have, but what's your take
there?
Um, no. No one's really talked about it.
And I I don't think this is uh
I don't think this is people just not
being aware of it or not being uh I
don't know scared of the fact that it
started and I think the reality is oil
doesn't budge and even though we had a r
you know we we jumped
I if if oil and this is the beauty of
markets we heard the doom and gloomer
say it should go to 200
let's haircut that and Hey, it should
have gone to 150.
The problem is it's still despite
everything and it's not just the front
part of the curve, it's the back end.
There are no issues. The thing that I
take from this is is plain and simple
there. We were supposed to have gas
prices surging. Now, again, crack
spreads are wide. And the reason crack
spreads are wide and so people
understand what crack spreads are, it's
the differential between the gas price
and the oil price. the conversion from
oil into gas that is still high. So the
ability of having gasoline is the issue
that is still still there but oil as a
whole is not going higher and I think
everyone would treat it as a short-term
thing. They don't think this is going to
not end. Uh meaning this is a flare up.
I think everyone had built into their
expectations this. So, I'll just say to
everyone here, unless we see surprising
movements in oil where it actually goes
higher, it still acts in the market at
something that has a positive negative.
And I hate to say this, it acts like
there's a glut. It literally acts like
when this ends, the price is going to
head back to 50. So, I'm not saying that
is going to happen. I'm just saying the
way the market looks and the way it
acts, it just doesn't act like something
that's going to go significantly higher.
So I think we're stuck between 65 and
80. And unless we get above 80 and the
Iran situation is worsening where
there's no ships going through Hormuz, I
just don't think it matters for the
markets.
>> The last thing I want to talk about for
a couple minutes is um I don't know if
you saw the 1X robotic hand demo.
>> No.
>> So um maybe the best way I can describe
this is the hand has been the hardest
part of robotics for a very long time.
30, 40 years people have been working on
this and most people what they
essentially have done is they have used
robotic components to build the hand.
But if you think of your hand, it is all
operated off of tendons. And so 1X
essentially has created a synthetic
version of a tendon-based robotic hand.
And in this demo, you know, they can do
very kind of ampidextrious, you know,
type uh type things or very dextterous
type things. But more importantly is it
can screw on a light bulb. It can pick a
cherry without, you know, going and
smashing it or it can do things that I
think a lot of people when they saw saw
this demo, the video got millions of
views online or like whoa, hold on a
second here. This is a significant leap
forward.
My takeaway from seeing this is that
everything that you and I are excited
about from an AI perspective, I would be
shocked if that robotic hand was not
somehow either ideiated or developed
using AI. And so we now are getting the
like, you know, second boost to this
robotic stuff where people are having
this super intelligent software to help
them make these advancements. And it
wouldn't shock me at all if we start to
see some pretty crazy stuff happen where
these robots start to be as humanlike as
maybe we all feared that they could, you
know, eventually get to.
>> Mhm. So, I'm going to And this is what
this is a Finnish company, right? Or a
Norwegian company.
>> I think the I think that it is made in
the United States. Uh but I think the
founders might be from there. I I can't
remember. There's something that is like
a Nordic relationship. Uh but I don't
think that the company is based. I think
it's actually a US company, but maybe
the founders are from there.
>> So, I I'm going to I agree with what you
said and and so people hear this. Um,
I'll start with a statement and then I'm
going to work a little backwards towards
why this isn't, you know, why ROIC for
for hyperscalers is not like fracking in
oil. Um, in in in this context. Uh, so
first of all, Anony's point is really
important, which I agree with. We're
underestimating that as we get to 100,
we're above 140 IQ now. As we get above
160, and as we get above 200, we will be
solving problems that we haven't been
able to solve. We'll take angles that
will allow us to produce these things.
And then once the humanoids are
available, then we also don't have to do
the physical work of testing it out.
They can build them for us. So the hand
is critical because it's probably the
worst thing we have for actually doing
intricate work that would be necessary
for robots to be making robots or robots
to be solving the problem. So if the
intelligence is there, we do need the
hands to be able to have them go. And
this was on a moonshots where uh Dave
Blondon basically admitted that he
underestimated how quickly we will get
billions of robots because he he saw at
Tesla, oh my gosh, the robots will be
building the robots at some point. This
is the compounding side that goes with
Opus 4.5 leads to 4.6 which leads to 4.7
and this whole thing of recursive
self-improvement. Now the reason I want
to bring this back is to oil. I was
asked by someone this week that isn't
the ROIC risk for the hyperscalers the
same as what happened with uh fracking
with the reason being and a a bunch of
people on VEX have posted this. They've
scared the hell out of some of my
subscribers. They've reached out. Here's
the reality guys. This is not
intelligence is not the same as oil.
Like I don't I don't know how to like
make that clear. Oil is oil.
Intelligence is everything. Meaning the
price of tokens going down, the usage
goes higher. Oil usage only grows in a
linear fashion related to nominal GDP.
It is a physical constraint to get more
of it. The problem is for intelligence,
it's the usage is growing exponentially.
Oil never grows exponentially
demand-wise. The only thing that slows
down AI is the data centers. It's the
gas turbines. It's the physical stuff
which cannot be made quickly. So to
Anony's point and for all of you that
are not understanding how the
compounding will go towards solving the
energy problem and why I always have one
eye on crude because eventually crude
will go to zero. It will go to zero
because we will solve energy at the
fision fusion. Name anything you want.
We will come up with so many solutions
going forward. And so when you listen to
Daario and you listen to Sam Alman and
you listen to Greg Brockman, they're all
saying the same thing, which is the
intelligence in getting us to a point
where math is being solved. Once math is
being solved, then cancer can be solved.
Then energy can be solved. These are all
the science problems. These are all the
physics problems of getting us to the
point where everything can compound. So,
in the same way we're talking about the
compounding of intelligence and models
for coding, which is language, we're
about to get into it with consumer
agents, and we're also about to get it
into science. And that's where the
robotics thing in the humanoids gets so
important for your investment decision-m
and it also feeds in why the financial
guardrails are necessary to deal with
this type of speed.
>> I think that's a great place for us to
end it. What um what are you going to
cover in your YouTube video this Sunday?
I'm I'm going to harp on the fact uh
number one that the AM midcycle slowdown
is over in the face that I think the
sentiment has dropped off enough the
volatility's gone high enough that we
are in the bottom end of the
consolidation and you should not should
now be thinking instead of is this going
lower now you should be thinking with
the AI trade which I couldn't say when
Micron was at 1300 but at 950 will it be
higher 6 months from now yes it will
once we get through two earning cycle it
will be higher Uh so the sixmon look
forward from this you're at the bottom
end of the range not the top end of the
range. Second thing is how important
consumer agents are to compute. For all
of you scared about compute thinking
there's a chance there's excess compute.
If you guys want to hammer me in the
future I will say this again. We have
insatiable demand for compute. We do not
have enough supply. And the argument I
just gave you, compute demand is
exponential because intelligence usage
goes up dramatically with every model
advancement, but the physical supply is
what constrains us. So this is a supply
demand mismatch and I'm going to go
through why that means you should be
invested there. And then thirdly, I will
go in more detail on this Bessin speech
and I will focus again on the importance
of Bitcoin because I do believe that a
year from now, we will be talking about
crypto in the same way that we're
talking about memory. And I'm going to
finalize it with what you said. You
asked me the question, are fundamental
people starting to No, they are not
focused on this right now. Number one,
because they're still focused on AI,
both from a loss perspective and what's
happened the last four weeks, but also
from what should we be buying down here.
Once they recognize and get through the
Fed and they get through all of the
changes, they are going to need to focus
on crypto and the financial guardrails
of the future. And six months from now
as we go into next year, crypto will be
the memory for next year.
>> Man, that got me hyped up. Journey, I'll
be watching.
We'll talk again next week.